RG 062:064 Town of Hartford
Connecticut State Library
Town of Hartford records
circa 1821-1936
Connecticut State Library
Hartford (Conn.)
258 cubic feet
Administrative, tax, land, and election records for the town of Hartford.
RG062_064
Multiple
Historical Note
The town of Hartford was settled in 1635 and incorporated in 1784. The city was incorporated in May 1784. Town and city consolidated in April 1896.
Scope and Content
Administrative, tax, land, and election records for the town of Hartford.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Soldiers -- Connecticut -- Hartford; Voting registers -- Connecticut -- Hartford; Tax assessment -- Connecticut -- Hartford -- Registers; Taxation -- Connecticut -- Hartford -- Registers; Local taxation -- Connecticut -- Hartford -- Registers; Property tax -- Connecticut -- Hartford -- Registers
Places:
Hartford (Conn.) -- Records and correspondence
Restrictions on Access
Boxes 2-3 are restricted due to condition. Please contact State Archives staff for assistance.
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Container List
- Reecords, circa 1821-1936
  - T000381
    - Town Treasurers' military payment records including payments for militia service, Foot Guard and Horse Guard returns, vouchers for payment From Soldiers' Fund and Conscript Relief Fund, circa 1854-1879 (Box Boxes 1-3)
      Boxes 2-3 are restricted due to condition.
    - Public Parks Department annual reports, 1896-1902 (Box Box 4)
    - Fire Department records including bills, Receipts, correspondence, reports and records of the Firemen's Ball Committee, circa 1821-1862 (Box Box 4)
    - Report on proposed sites for new municipal building, and blueprints, undated (Box Box 4)
    - Lists of electors
      Lists of electors are not boxed.
      - 1874, 1 volume
      - 1875, 1 volume
      - Part 1, 1876; 1 volume
      - Part 2, 1876; 1 volume
      - 1878 April, 1 volume
      - 1878 October, 1 volume
      - 1879 April, 1 volume
      - 1879 October, 1 volume
      - 1880 April, 1 volume
      - 1880 October, 1 volume
      - 1881 April, 1 volume
      - 1881 October, 1 volume
      - 1882 April, 1 volume
      - 1883 April, 1 volume
      - 1884 April, 1 volume
      - 1885 April, 1 volume
      - 1886 April, 1 volume
      - 1887 April, 1 volume
      - 1887 October, 1 volume
      - 1888 April, 1 volume
      - 1888 October, 1 volume
      - 1889 April, 1 volume
      - 1889 October, 1 volume
      - 1890 April, 1 volume
      - 1890 October, 1 volume
      - 1891 April, 1 volume
      - 1892 October, 1 volume
      - 1893 April, 1 volume
      - 1893 October, 1 volume
      - 1894 April, 1 volume
      - 1894 October, 1 volume
      - 1895 April, 1 volume
      - 1895 October, 1 volume
      - 1896 April, 1 volume
      - 1896 November, 1 volume
      - 1897 April, 1 volume
      - 1898 April, 1 volume
      - 1898 November, 1 volume
      - 1899 April, 1 volume
      - 1900 April, 1 volume
      - 1900 November, 1 volume
      - 1901 April, 1 volume
      - 1902 April, 1 volume
      - 1902 November, 1 volume
      - 1903 April, 1 volume
      - 1904 April, 1 volume
      - 1904 November, 1 volume
      - 1905 April, 1 volume
      - 1906 April, 1 volume
      - 1906 November, 1 volume
      - 1907 April, 1 volume
      - 1908 April, 1 volume
      - 1908 November, 1 volume
      - 1909 April, 1 volume
      - 1910 April, 1 volume
      - 1910 November, 1 volume
      - 1936 November, 1 roll (Box Box 5)
        On oversize shelving.
    - Ballots, Ward 7, District 2, 1908 (Map-case Map drawer 4)
    - Assessment Department records ("street books")
      Volumes for 1882 to 1918 are not boxed.
      - 1863-1864 (Box Box 6)
        The cover is labeled 1865.
      - 1865 (Box Box 6)
        The cover is labeled 1866.
      - 1871, 1872, 1873 (Box Box 7)
      - 1874, 1875, 1876 (Box Box 8)
      - 1877, 1878, 1879 (Box Box 9)
      - 1880, 1881 (Box Box 10)
      - 1882, 1 volume
      - 1883, 1 volume
      - 1884, 1 volume
      - 1885, 1 volume
      - 1886, 1 volume
      - 1887, 1 volume
      - 1888, 1 volume
      - 1889, 1 volume
      - 1890, 1 volume
      - 1891, 1 volume
      - 1892, 1 volume
      - 1893, 1 volume
      - 1894, 1 volume
      - 1895, 1 volume
      - 1896, 1 volume
      - 1897, 1 volume
      - Assessors Office re-assessment book, 1897; 1 volume
      - 1898, 1 volume
      - 1899, 1 volume
      - 1900, 1 volume
      - 1901, 1 volume
      - 1902, 1 volume
      - 1903, 1 volume
      - 1904, 1 volume
      - 1905, 1 volume
      - 1906, 1 volume
      - 1907, 1 volume
      - 1908, 1 volume
      - 1909, 1 volume
      - 1910, 1 volume
      - 1911, 1 volume
      - 1912, 1 volume
      - 1914, 1 volume
      - 1915, 1 volume
      - 1916, 1 volume
      - 1917, 1 volume
      - 1918, 1 volume
    - Individual tax lists
      - 1878, 1879, 1880 (Box Box 11)
    - Property transfer registers
      - 1877-1878 (Box Box 12)
        Cover is labeled 1878 only.
      - 1879 October 1-1880 October 1 (Box Box 12)
    - Tax abstracts ("assessment books"), 1850-1920
      Tax abstracts for 1880 to 1920 are not boxed.
      - 1850, 1851, 1852 (Box Box 13)
      - 1853, 1854, 1855 (Box Box 14)
      - 1856, 1857 (Box Box 15)
      - 1858, 1859 (Box Box 16)
      - 1860, 1861 (Box Box 17)
      - 1862, 1863 (Box Box 18)
      - 1864, 1865 (Box Box 19)
      - 1866, 1867 (Box Box 20)
      - 1868, 1869 (Box Box 21)
      - 1870 (Box Box 22)
      - 1871, 2 copies (Box Box 23)
      - 1872 (Box Box 24)
      - 1873, 2 copies (Box Box 25)
      - 1873 (3rd copy), 1874 (1st copy) (Box Box 26)
      - 1874, 2 copies (Box Box 27)
      - 1875, 2 copies (Box Box 28)
      - 1876, 2 copies (Box Box 29)
      - 1877, 2 copies (Box Box 30)
      - 1877 (3rd copy), 1878 (1st copy) (Box Box 31)
      - 1878, 2 copies (Box Box 32)
      - 1879, 2 copies (Box Box 33)
      - 1879, (3rd copy) (Box Box 34)
      - 1880, 2 duplicate volumes
      - 1881, 3 duplicate volumes
      - 1882, 3 duplicate volumes
      - 1883, 3 duplicate volumes
      - 1884, 3 duplicate volumes
      - 1885, 3 duplicate volumes
      - 1886, 3 duplicate volumes
      - 1887, 3 duplicate volumes
      - 1888, 3 duplicate volumes
      - 1889, 2 duplicate volumes
      - 1890, 2 duplicate volumes
      - 1891, 2 duplicate volumes
      - 1892, 2 duplicate volumes
      - 1893, 2 duplicate volumes
      - 1894, 2 duplicate volumes
      - 1895, 3 duplicate volumes
      - 1896, 2 duplicate volumes
      - 1897, 2 duplicate volumes
      - 1898, 1 volume
      - 1899, 1 volume
      - 1900, 1 volume
      - 1901, 1 volume
      - 1902, 1 volume
      - 1903, 1 volume
      - 1904, 1 volume
      - 1905, 1 volume
      - 1906
        - A-K, 1 volume (1st copy)
        - L-Z, 1 volume (1st copy)
        - A-K, 1 volume (2nd copy)
        - L-Z, 1 volume (2nd copy)
      - 1907
        - A-K, 1 volume (1st copy)
        - L-Z, 1 volume (1st copy)
        - A-K, 1 volume (2nd copy)
        - L-Z, 1 volume (2nd copy)
      - 1908
        - A-K, 1 volume (1st copy)
        - L-Z, 1 volume (1st copy)
        - A-K, 1 volume (2nd copy)
        - L-Z, 1 volume (2nd copy)
      - 1909
        - A-K, 1 volume (1st copy)
        - L-Z, 1 volume (1st copy)
        - A-K, 1 volume (2nd copy)
        - L-Z, 1 volume (2nd copy)
      - 1910
        - A-K, 1 volume (1st copy)
        - L-Z, 1 volume (1st copy)
        - A-K, 1 volume (2nd copy)
        - L-Z, 1 volume (2nd copy)
      - 1911
        - A-K, 1 volume (1st copy)
        - L-Z, 1 volume (1st copy)
        - A-K, 1 volume (2nd copy)
        - L-Z, 1 volume (2nd copy)
      - 1912
        - A-K, 1 volume (1st copy)
        - L-Z, 1 volume (1st copy)
        - A-K, 1 volume (2nd copy)
        - L-Z, 1 volume (2nd copy)
      - 1913
        - A-K, 1 volume (1st copy)
        - L-Z, 1 volume (1st copy)
        - A-K, 1 volume (2nd copy)
        - L-Z, 1 volume (2nd copy)
      - 1914
        - A-K, 1 volume (1st copy)
        - L-Z, 1 volume (1st copy)
        - A-K, 1 volume (2nd copy)
        - L-Z, 1 volume (2nd copy)
      - 1915
        - A-K, 1 volume (1st copy)
        - L-Z, 1 volume (1st copy)
        - A-K, 1 volume (2nd copy)
        - L-Z, 1 volume (2nd copy)
      - 1916
        - A-K, 1 volume (1st copy)
        - L-Z, 1 volume (1st copy)
        - A-K, 1 volume (2nd copy)
        - L-Z, 1 volume (2nd copy)
      - 1917
        - A-K, 1 volume (1st copy)
        - L-Z, 1 volume (1st copy)
        - A-K, 1 volume (2nd copy)
        - L-Z, 1 volume (2nd copy)
      - 1918
        - A-K, 1 volume (1st copy)
        - L-Z, 1 volume (1st copy)
        - A-K, 1 volume (2nd copy)
        - L-Z, 1 volume (2nd copy)
      - 1919
        - A-K, 1 volume (1st copy)
        - L-Z, 1 volume (1st copy)
        - A-K, 1 volume (2nd copy)
        - L-Z, 1 volume (2nd copy)
      - 1920
        - A-K, 1 volume
        - L-Z, 1 volume
    - Abstract of property
      - 1874-1885, 1 volume
        Labeled No.2 on spine
      - 1882-1890, 1 volume
        Labeled No.3 on spine
  - T003140
    - Land records, 1901-1924; 93 volumes
  - 1986-017
    - Land records, 1901-1924; 113 volumes
  - 2002-066, 1 folder
    stored in shared hollinger
    - Public Parks Department annual report, 1900-1901